use a partial cookie injection and turn
it into a full cookie injection where we
control the key to um just with like
partial cookie injection so you'll need
to have inject three cookies
right M what are you doing man
[Music]
[Applause]
sup guys this is a continuation episode
of last week um the topic is not related
at all but it was something that we
planed to put into one episode um but we
just didn't quite fit it in TimeWise so
um this week we're going to be talking
with Matan again about some cookie
related quirks um potentially how to
convert a partial cookie injection um
into a full cookie injection and some
other quirks around browser parsing of
of cookies and the amazing uh caching
related writeups from Kevin Mizu with
the uh hero CTF so hope you guys enjoy
this
episode all right man here we go we're
back yeah uh new episode our poor our
poor um our poor editor I can't I can't
put too much strain on him because that
was a long episode as we always do um
but yeah let's let's definitely I
definitely still wanted to get to some
of these awesome things you had in the
dock here um so so let's hit let's hit
the two cookie pieces and then we'll go
and talk about um the the caching stuff
that first cookie trick I love that's
really mindblowing and super useful so
in certain
environments um specifically I've looked
at Java environments just because that's
like what my targets used at the time um
but they have pretty weird cookie
parsing logic
especially when it comes to um quotes So
what they have is basically a way to
have a quoted value of a cookie so if
there's some um character that would
normally be problematic in the value of
a cookie like a
semicolon what they do is they put
quotes around the value of the cookie so
you have like key equals key equals
value in the cookie you can have what
they do is they have um key equals and
then quotes around the value and then
even if the value is like um weird um
characters it will pass it
correctly correctly as in not complying
at all with the
RFC yeah like that I mean I haven't read
the RFC so maybe it's compatible I'm not
it's a it's a legacy thing from from an
older version of of the RFC um yeah
interesting so it was correct at some
point it was anyways um it it might be
correct it's
exploitable okay the scenarios where
it's exploitable is
one in those um environments okay you
might have a scenario where you want to
comment cookies okay and what I mean by
that is um say you want to exploit the
um sort of self exess
and like we mentioned in the previous
previous episode that you had with me um
so if you want to exploit that in a Java
environment a lot of the time it's
problematic because the value that these
that these environments prefer is sort
of the latter value if you have two
cookies with the same key they'll prefer
the the latter one and not the first one
like it's like usually happens and it's
very hard to get your malicious cookie
to come after the um legitimate cookie
so what you can do um if you want it to
prefer your value so to do what's called
cookie
tossing um if you have a way to set
cookies in the Target you can set all of
your cookies that you want and then set
like an as the last cookie a equals
quote and now um it will read everything
after the um a cookie unless those
cookies have like quotes in them which
is is going to mess up stuff because
then it will close your quotes stuff
like that very annoying I had to deal
with that a lot the last time I tried to
exploit it yeah man it was crazy I like
started Shifting the order of the
cookies stuff like that well it It's
Tricky right because because you and
I'll just I'll just talk about this for
a second the order of the cookies is
determined by the path length for
right and the chronological order the
the chronological order so if you're
setting it super recently like if you're
you're getting it set it's not even the
original time it was set it was the last
time it was set so if they changed the
value it's sort of a reset yeah yeah so
that I mean that's that's helpful to
exploit um but what I didn't realize
before I was prepping for this episode
was that this is for some reason I had
it in my head that the order was not
just based on the path link it was order
like ordered based off of like some
other thing like um you know
alphabetical or something like that I
looked for that desperately I couldn't
find any other and it's it's literally
just the path link so if you want your
cookie to become to come first very very
first all you have to do is just set a a
a very very very specific path length
and dude I spent I I always tell myself
all right I'm just only going to spend
like you know a couple hours prepping
for the episode and then I'm going to
like get along with my life no because
what happens is you get in these
scenarios and you start researching this
stuff and then you're like ah wait a
second I need to go see if I can figure
out a way to artificially inflate the
path size so that it on on a cookie so
that you can force it to the front even
if you have another um I mean cookie
that has a very explicit path set but
you can always be more specific you can
uh pick like all of the end points that
you're trying to exploit and set like a
different cookie for each of those yeah
unless the actual endpoint the actual
business logic also sets that
that's going to be very like setting for
a specific Endo it's be I seen it though
I have seen it before and and um and so
I was looking into this I was looking
into this and I couldn't figure it out
except for one little nice little Nuance
which is um often times uh web servers
will decode the percent TF in the URL
right oh so resets it yeah so so yeah
yeah it doesn't yeah if you do if you
encode slash as percent 2 F and and you
set your cookie it makes it longer to
have a perc 2 F then instead of Slash
then that will inflate the size of your
cookie can you do SL SL uh I tried that
you can't do it it won't it won't send
it um which is annoying but uh because
there's like it's almost like you're
dealing with front end back end within
the browser itself because it does
normalization of those path of the the
browser URL before it it actually
Compares it to the path so I I tried to
do like path traversals and like Dot
traversals and stuff like like that but
the browser is like no no no it's not
going to happen so you have to you have
to um as far as my research went you
have to um take advantage of a
discrepancy between the the way that the
server is parsing the path and the way
that the browser is parsing the path and
then set your cookie in conjunction with
that with that path does that make sense
yeah yeah so so you can actually get
your very very Niche but that's what
that's what we talk about here on the
Pod um all you can all you can just have
it be sort of the same spec
specificity like the same level of
specific and somehow make it re refresh
the cookie refresh yeah yeah that's true
and the sort of trick with refreshing
cookies to get them to the end is the
same thing I did back when I tried to
comment cookies with the um extra quote
the hanging quote and had a bunch of
cookies that were that had quotes in
them that were interfering with that so
what I did first of all I try to predict
the value of some of these cookies and
set it without quotes Okay myself before
the attack so now the server is going to
see when it tries to set the cookie is G
it's going to see that the cookie is
already set with the correct value and
it's not going to set the cookie with
quotes Okay so that like eliminates
those that I can predict and I had one
cookie that I couldn't predict the value
of but I found some end point that would
reset the value of that cookie like
update it so when I make the victim or
when the victim naturally interacts with
that end point that cookie is going to
get like popped to the um like to the
end of the string to the yeah to the end
of the string and because it's the
newest set yeah and then I'm going to
have like my um hanging quote and then
it will quote all of the important
cookies up to that cookie that's in at
the end
yeah this may yeah it it's sort of
reminds me of those scenarios those
double injection reflected xss scenarios
where you have a limited character set
and you need to have two injection
points um and and you know you're you're
or or maybe even if you're doing
something this is more more applicable
if you're doing like a dingling markup
attack right where where you're leaving
it open and the rest of that stuff is
getting put into an HTML attribute we're
using sort of similar logic here to
comment out cookies that are are
preceding um are after our our malicious
input inputed cookie right what's more
fun is the scenarios where you have the
same injection in two places and then
you have like a dangling markup and then
that same character closes that markup
in the other payload then it's oh my
gosh dude yeah that's that gets very
intense and you can do like comments and
stuff like that too um and and when we
were when we were prepping for this I I
was thinking about this whole scenario
and I think I figured out a really
really helpful way to get to use these
sort of gadgets right that was a great
way like really like that one I'm
excited to tell people about this okay
so here's the idea and I'm I'll go ahead
and um and share my screen here uh so I
so I can people can see the um the
actual um representation of it uh right
here um and so essentially what the way
that we we utilize this
is we have the ability to set an
arbitrary cookie right and that cookie
where wherever it is has a allows us to
set whatever value we want so we have
complete control of the value of the
cookie um uh and so what we can do is
make the first value uh the first
character of that cookie equal to the
double quote right which will trigger
this weird double quote um cookie
functionality that's present in a lot of
java libraries and some python libraries
as well and so that will um now make the
characters like semicolon
non-terminating for these cookies and
then um what we can do is leave that
that whole that that string open and set
another cookie with a uh a path that
aligns it right after this this cookie
and that also has the double quote on it
right so now we've quoted the beginning
of that cookie into of the second set
cookie into that that first cookie um
and then from there what happens that's
really cool is the value of that cookie
that we that we sent before becomes the
key for another cookie so we can convert
a a um scenario in which we have control
of the cookie uh value but not the
cookies key into a scenario where we can
smuggle an arbitrary cookie into the the
browser context which is a much more
impactful Gadget yeah and there might be
other ways to do that that um there has
been some research in that
area um I
remember um there being there's one that
you linked here but I think there was
another one maybe it was the
um the one that was one of the um top
10 yeah yeah I think I remember
something like that I'm not 100% sure
but that's something that I will look at
after this episode and yeah but yeah and
one one very like practical attack
scenario for the trick you just
mentioned is if you have um what's
called like a partial cookie injection
so you have let's say in JavaScript an
injection into a cookie where you can
only control the value but you can
inject like semicolons after it and
control like a few attributes yeah um
which we we're also going to talk about
that scenario in a second yeah yeah in
another context but yeah if you have
that um
then you can um set like the cookie that
you want first to come first with the
like um ding markup you can set it and
then specify a specific path that will
make it come first and then you can set
your cookie right um and it will be set
like after the session cookie was set
when the user logged in right so you
will set it um with
like
um a double a double quote you will set
it without a specific path or with a
less specific part or something like
that depending on where you want it to
end up and then you have like um you
have two things one you have an
injection of a cookie with whatever name
you want right and um I think that's
possible uh because one thing that
might DP you up is um do you have to in
that case um inject a
semicolon
somewhere for for segmenting off the the
cookie or you talking about because you
have like the opening the opening markup
yeah and then in the second cookie that
comes after you have the closing markup
but I'm not sure if you can put like
another cookie straight after it or if
you have to have like a semicolon are
you talking about in the set cookie
header or are you talking about the way
that this is being represented from the
server when the way the server is
passing it yeah you do need the
semicolon there there are some there's
some research and it's actually in that
same blog by then I'm not sure I'm not
sure that is possible
but what will be possible is to set like
a dangling mark up at the start and um
with a very not specific path uh then
markup at the end and then you have like
a cookie with a name that you
control um having like the victim
session token and all of that yeah even
if they smug into a different a
different which is mentioned in the blog
that you linked Yeah by enur Sara and
we'll L that link that as well there's a
lot of very interesting takeaways here
but it's a great area of research
because the parsing is just so different
between the client and the server in
this case really is and and it's a
pretty Niche scenario where you have
this sort of double quote thing but Java
is used a lot and there's a good amount
of python libraries too I want to say um
the research by uh Sara mentioned that
yeah Cherry py web.py AO HTTP server
which is used oftentimes um and a bunch
of other ones will parse these double
quotes quotes yeah and and so we're
we're talking about Python and Java
environment here in a in a lot of ways
um so this could be one of the things
that this could be one of the things we
could maybe build an extension for and
and see like okay we've got our session
token or whatever right if we double
quote it does it does it h still have a
valid session or does it not and that
could determine whether or not we have
that double quote C I think I think I
figured out how we can smuggle a an just
like a a cookie with use a partial
cookie injection and turn it into a full
cookie injection where we control the
key to um just with like a partial
cookie injection so you'll need to have
inject three cookies
right M what are you doing man okay
first cookie is we'll call it first
equals and then just like an opening
quote and you put that at the start
right after that cookie with a bit less
of a specific path or maybe they can all
be the same specificity you just need to
set them one after the other logically
so right after that cookie you'll set
second equals and then um just a closing
quotes
right oh wait no that might not work
because then no it it should work the
double quote will be a part of the value
because it isn't at the beginning yeah
but I I thought about using like the
semicolon that sort of ends that cookie
but then we're back when we started
because um the Third cookie that we
inject after that closing quote will not
we will not have control over its name I
I think I think it should work with just
two cookies right because we here I I'll
I'll type then you'll have to I'll in
the do hold on M hold on let me let me
let me type it in the doc really quickly
and then and then I think this should
work so let's say we have a cookie x
equals uh x equals double quote right
and then we you know whatever and then
we set another cookie which is y equals
um uh double quote or like a double
quote right or or whatever right so now
this middle area right here this is the
value for x yeah but I think or this is
actually that comes after that might
still be part of x no it it it because
we can put the semicolon
here I don't think you can inject a
semicolon in the value of a cookie
because then you will just be able to do
like x equals a semicolon and then
whatever you want right you won't even
need to have the quote stuff oh think
the browser isn't going
to otherwise you won't need to have the
quote stuff anyways so so then we have
to do rely on what what um Sara was
talking about with the space or
something with spaces or with some other
delimiter which is only happening in a
very limited subset we're figuring this
out while we're recording the episode we
are we are we getting a very raw like
sample of the process yeah that that's
great okay we thought we got it like
three different times yeah um Prett sure
so then the browser is going to is going
to dang it dude this is this is so close
but but I feel like there in some
scenarios there will be um a a way that
you can actually result in I think some
of the parcels will like see the just
like um my intuition is some parcels
will see like the closing uh quote and
we'll and we'll think like oh that's the
end of that value now here begins
another cookie right and in in those
cases you will just be able to inject
more cookies and yeah I think there were
two two scenarios where that was the
case in it doesn't work at least on the
targets that I've looked at okay solid
so so there's there's a very Niche
scenario then coming off of all this
where you have to combine the double
quote parsing with some some sort of
loose representation of what a
Terminator of the cookie value is in
order to convert a partial cookie
injection into a full cookie
injection yeah nice very gadgety stuff
very very Gadget heavy stuff as as we
always do here on critical thinking um
yeah I love it um okay solid well that
it's an interesting approach nonetheless
and and the gadget I think is is really
useful um because you control the order
of cookies too with with the path
attribute if you can just comment out
the rest of the the the cookies with the
double quote right because because you
can do the same sort of thing with what
you were talking about where you can um
in two episodes ago right at this point
where you can just make your make a
different person authenticated for a
specific endpoint and and that s very
cool comment out all the other cookies
that might cause a problem yeah uh I
think I think that's a really good way
to approach this as far as exploitation
goes so talking about commenting stuff M
okay yeah great segue into the next
section uhuh yeah let's do it there's a
very weird
Behavior maybe got changed since the
last time I tested it I don't think it
it it did and this is a behavior in
Safari which by the way I've recently um
got um a nice way to debug safari stuff
and because I don't have a Mac and I
tried to buy like a very old Mac to test
Safari on specifically because I knew
just had too many quirks um but that was
very very slow um so what I did and I
very recommend it I highly recommend it
I enjoyed it um you if you have an
iPhone um you can connect that phone and
you have to install iTunes on your
computer um but you can connect that
phone to your computer enable debugging
on your phone and then use some Google
tool I think it's called um debug web
kit proxy or something like that debug
web kit proxy and yeah iOS web kit debug
proxy right I'll I'll drop the link in
the um in the episode in the notes um
but you can use that tool and it will
connect to the
um it will connect to the phone and now
you can use yeah and now you can use um
uh Dev tool front end um and you need
that to use the Safari Dev tools front
end and there are some people that have
like extracted that front end from the
web kit source code and so you can have
like a Windows version of it and now you
can basically have remote debugging on
your phone without a Mac okay so this
this is this is a way for you to test
Safari related bugs on just an iPhone
and it's kind of like remote debugging
for Chrome Dev tools but it's it's
specifically for for Safari mhm nice and
um so it's very useful to test this sort
of stuff and you can like interact with
it physically and you you use like the
same computer and you don't have to move
to a different setup and
anyways uh the one very weird and quirky
Behavior I found in Safari is that um we
had actually it was a collab with you we
had a specific um ended very tragically
but anyways we had a an injection into
uh the value of a cookie and we could
insert H
like commas or what's it called um the
semicolon semicolon yeah yeah forgot
what it's called um but we can we could
insert semicolons and insert attributes
so we have like cookie attribute
injection yeah the problem was that we
had other attributes like the path
attributes and all the fun attributes
that we wanted to specify they were
specified in the sort of original
statement that we were inject that we
were injecting into the way it works
yeah attributes the browser specifies
the L occurence so we needed some way of
commenting out all of the attributes
that came after our injection point and
I found that in Safari if you inject the
weird special character after the um
after your injection point so you just
go comma part equal something Comm your
semicolon yeah semicolon sorry um
semicolon your um pathal something and
then semicolon and then the uh character
I found that the closing kly bracket
Wass I think character but absolutely
insane super weird and and then it will
just ignore all of the rest of the
attributes which is it's nuts I mean I
would think that if such an error Ur
during parsing it would just ignore the
whole cookie setting statement right
throw some error or something but yeah
they sort of sweep it under the rug and
you have like this sort of half error
that causes very weird behavior that
just comments out the rest of it it's
almost like a like a a JavaScript you
know block comment or whatever that just
comments out the rest of the but I mean
even a block comment you can just like
put it in there like a blow comment you
need to close it out somewhere right
yeah it's nuts dude that that and it's
crazy that that the it's such an
unexpected character um as well I mean I
just I tried to fuzz it a little bit and
this is just the first one I found the
first one that hit was the the closing
curly bracket yeah it's it's very Niche
but it's really helpful and what was
weirder to me about this situation is as
we were collabing on it we were like ah
we need a way to like get rid of these
attributes that are on the end so we can
do the cookie tossing properly blah blah
blah and um and and I remember the
moment combined the two we combined the
two things here right we had both quot
and the yeah nice very and um and you
turn to me and you're like I bet Safari
has some weird [__] with this and I'm
like and I'm like you know why I did
that how do you know that baton like
what like a few a few days before that I
was collabing with Johan on some um some
stuff in one of the targets that we HCK
together and um it was like on um a
specific like context in JavaScript and
he just noticed because I think because
he um has a mark he just noticed that
Safari has a certain Global variable
accessible that other browsers don't in
that case and I was like it was very
weird and unexpected and it sort of made
me think about all the other bugs that I
missed that were exploitable because of
a weird Safari issue yeah man Safari's
whack that's why I decided to test it I
I bought a Mech right after Johan
discovered that little trick and haven't
used it but yeah pays for itself
immediately when you when you find all
these weird little things that allow you
to exploit these edge cases um yeah man
that that is one of the things I'm glad
GL you mentioned the piece about being
able to use that debugging um on the
iPhone because that is one of the things
that I'm a little sad about yeah about
not having a Mac is like you
just you can't test weird stuff with
Safari and I've tried using I think it's
called browser stack they they will like
give you a that's very annoying though
they're super expensive and there's
always a delay yeah and and and I dude I
set it up it was crazy cuz I set it up
and I was like wow this is amazing this
is so easy and they give you like one
minute of three times so I'm like I'm
like rushing to try to like f something
really
quickly and then you know the fuzz is
running and then it's shut down you I'm
like no by the way we're such weird
consumers I assume we're one of the only
people that have like we're unable to
debug Safari
as why we we said we don't have a Mac
absolutely man yeah I think um I think
it might be worthwhile to just I mean
it's definitely worthwhile to just have
an iPad or an iPhone or something like
that that you can connect to and then
use this um debugging tool but it may
just be worthwhile to to get my hands on
an old Mac just to play around with
safari stuff for sure yeah um okay was
there anything else on that so we've got
a away we've got we've sort of got away
a very Niche way to convert a partial
cookie injection into a full cookie
injection um and just using this concept
of the double quotes and we have a way
to comment out stuff in in all in um in
a specific set of web servers that was
the first thing we talked about and then
you've got a specific niche in Safari
which is when the the cookie is coming
back from the server side um in the set
cookie header where you can um comment
out some of the attributes is that is
that an accurate summary yeah okay and I
mean there isn't anything else in the
doc but if you want we can do um a
reducted report section yeah well we we
can do that uh but let's actually let's
go talk about some of this stuff that
popped up with um with Mizu and this CTF
that this hero CTF 6 because because
um yeah this was crazy I'm not a huge
CTF guy but there's so many nice gadgets
that come out of CTF and I mean I'd love
to do that but I don't know how I can
find like the actual useful ctfs because
that aren't just you know another
reflected exercise challenge yeah yeah
you got to just hit up hit up here
whenever you you create a c whenever you
find a a cool challenge or create a cool
challenge just send the link to me I'd
appreciate it yeah for sure and and the
community can do that too just send m on
if you see a cool a cool I don't want to
just say the community tell the
community DM me yeah dude you're about
to get you're about to get my
notifications but RI dude yeah but yeah
that's what you signed up for man it's
already out there can't take it back so
so I'll um let me talk about the one the
the the interesting caching we're going
to talk about two caching related
functionalities um from this uh right up
that are gadgets that can be used and
then um and then we'll call it a wrap
because there's a bunch of stuff in here
uh and we're we're running long today um
but let me go ahead and share this right
up so we can get it on the screen for
those of you watching on YouTube I mean
this episode is only 30 minutes yeah it
should be fine I I I've got a bounce in
in a little bit but um we'll we'll go
through this um the the first one that I
kind of wanted to talk through was this
uh write up called medium Cash Cash uh
and and essentially this reminds me of a
a vulnerability that um was that have
had that's had several iterations that
that's mentioned here by by bitk where
you're essentially utilizing the forced
cach attribute of fetch to pull data out
of the cash that you wouldn't normally
be able to access by doing a normal
fetch request and the situation in which
um this is exploited is really Niche um
and it's made more difficult now by the
uh double key caching or cash
partitioning that was implemented in
Chrome uh a while back I think in like
2019 or 2020 um but essentially nowadays
these these caches are cash keys are
generated via three three parts it's the
top level window um the current window
ETL d+1 and then the full URL of the
loaded resources what what's lands into
this cache um and the the way that this
is abused in this specific scenario is
related to to how fetch is not allowed
to send uh credential requests to an
endpoint that has access control allow
origin star you you'll get an error if
that's the case so what is abused here
is um the the solver of the CTF sends
puts an image tag in with a source uh
pointing to the specific resource that
they want to to leak which cannot start
with a a curly bracket is noted um
because of Corb but um that will
actually load that specific spefic
resource into the cache and and that
request will be sent with setting with
the same site none cookies sent along
with it um and then you can load that
request from the cach using the cash
Force cach um setting in Fetch and then
read the response which you normally
wouldn't be able to do because fetch
can't send credential requests to an
access control all origin star endpoint
so essentially you're priming the
response with with the image tag um that
has the access control that ignores the
access control allow origin start thing
that you don't get any errors there and
then you bypass that by using the fetch
request to load the response directly
from the cache and since it's Access
Control allow Orin star you'll be able
to read it um and that response which
was created and cached with the same
site none cookies from the image um mat
I don't know can you can you check me
there did that was that that was yeah
that was um
that was accurate he says that was
really uh that was really um that was
really something Justin we're just
recording for so long I forgot how to
say accurate yeah I'm sorry dude I'm
sorry well are are you up to doing the
like what do you think about this one I
can still record I just um if we'll keep
going I'll need a short break but you're
you're good man yeah do do you want to
um it's very interesting what happens
here because you have like the um image
which sort of sense a request with
credentials but that you cannot read
right similar to a Fetch with mode no
course right um which it would be
interesting if you can actually use that
instead of the image maybe no course for
cash maybe I don't know um but you have
like a request that you can send with
credentials but cannot read the response
and the request that you can send
without credentials but read the
response and you Som and you sort of
combine these two so that the second
request will actually get the response
of the first one um from the cach very
interesting I've never thought about it
yeah and and I think they they exploit
it in this specific CTF environment
under a more nuanced environment because
some of the cookies are set to strict
and require you know it requires a
gadget an xss gadget on the the weite so
you're na you're sending this from a a
same site environment but I think this
is also exploitable in bug bounty in the
wild um in environments where there's
same site none but you're running into
that Access Control Star yeah problem
all in environments where there same
site locks or something and you have
like subdomain exercise yeah well that's
actually an interesting and it's an
interesting point too because I think at
the bottom of this right up there was an
unintended solution that somebody found
that uses window.open and and it does
window. open to that which is actually a
top level
navigation so I wonder oh and that stoes
it in the cach huh yeah makes sense so
you I didn't test that would the
browser um oh but then when you do
window. open you mention the three Cash
keys right yeah then the cash key of
like the top level URL or top level site
right yeah that would be different
between the
request that you want the cash for and
the request that retrieves the cash
because one of them is going to happen
from the attacker site and the other is
going to happen when you load the window
in and in this case because it's a
navigation it's going to be
um you see what I mean I do and and it's
TLD plus one though so it will it will
probably cash it but you won't be able
to retrieve that cash cross site right
you'll only be able to it same site okay
but how how was it different in this
case I mean I think I think I'm correct
but no you are correct it's because it's
same site and and the cat key so what
was the unintended solution in this case
why did it work it it it worked because
it's it's on Via nxss so so they still
used that Gadget so it's the same uh
prerequisites and the same impacts yeah
exactly so it doesn't that doesn't
actually that would have been crazy
though if you could do like a top level
navigation and then bypass uh
such a weird little attack surface here
and I mean I have thought in the past
about actually quite recently about um
what happens when you have a an
injection into like a fetch call so
basically you can specify like a URL
maybe with some restriction or something
and a bunch of options but you can't
read the response can you somehow use
the cach in that case and um that's a
trick man I aside aside from cash
poisoning um maybe you have like some
header that isn't in the cash key of
like the browser yeah um so that's sort
of client side cash poisoning if it
makes sense yeah that does make sense
that's then to be clear what I'm talking
about here he is um I don't know some
post message you sent on example.com
just injects into fetch right uh accepts
two parameters injects both of them into
fetch
then from um attacker.com you send a
post message that goes to SL example.com
reflect header.php and have like x- xss
colon and some um HTML injection payload
right and so the post message will be
like um the first argument would be that
URL and then you will have like in the
options headers and then specify the
headers and cach mode or cash colon
forse cash not cash mode and I think
what that would do I think would
um the cash key of that um like
malicious response or response that
contains HTML would be the um
example.com as the top level window
example.com is the current window and uh
example.com
reflect um as yeah so so then yeah so SL
reflect header so then when you initiate
a top level navigation to example.com
reflect header.php it would be the exact
same cach key right because it's still
under example.com still under
example.com in the current window and
still the same URL dang dude that's
interesting yeah huh
wow and I had that theoretical but I
didn't know like it was maybe two days
ago so weird documents that I've
actually all of our all of our episodes
like the longer they go they degrade
into like this is just us doing research
live on the podcast no but I mean it's
an idea that I had like maybe two days
ago which is crazy that all of this
research comes out like right after a
few days after that but um I thought
about it and I didn't actually have
such a gadget with a header header
reflection um when I sort of um when you
went after that yeah when I went after
that but so I didn't actually test it
but now that um actually understand how
the [__] work I don't see a reason why
not yeah yeah that makes sense dude wow
uh that's well you've got to weaken some
change before this episode airs so you
got to go got to go knock that
out first of all no body's GNA know
which Target that's in right second of
all I'm pretty lazy so maybe not I'll do
it next week I somehow I don't I don't
buy that much on considering no I mean I
get a lot of bugs but that's um that's a
different scenario I guess okay so let's
let's talk about this cash put thing and
then we'll call it a day so as as I
understand it this this um the the
situation with this was that there
there's this
caches um object that is being um
Exposed on the to to the actual page
that's normally used by service workers
um and this is for those of you
following along this is in the service
worker um pipe hijacking through cach
API section of the meu. write up um and
I'll go ahead and share my screen for
that as well um and essentially as I
what the domain name I I yeah I know
right um essentially on this one as I
understand it this allows you to take a
an xss that you have on a specific page
and use that to hijack any sort of
caching done via service workers um on
the domain where this xss triggers so
you can get xss across a lot of
different um endpoints and stuff like
that using using this technique is that
I mean is is that an accurate represent
there or am I am
iing you're good so if we do if we do
caches do. keys right on on the specific
scenario Uh Oh you mean the um the
service worker scenario yeah yeah yeah
yeah that one was also very cool because
the caches API the sort of main use case
for it is when you have a service worker
that tries to implement the cash right
and it sort of gives you more control
over it because you can manage the cash
keys and the respon and the responses
asso associated with them very directly
in the service worker so the the normal
usage for this is you have um a cach so
the way you get a reference to a cach is
you go caches do openen and then pass
some string to it which is the
identifier of the cach okay and then you
get a reference to it and you can add
requests to it and um responses an
interesting thing is you can use this
API as a sort of alternative to fetch so
um it has a a function if you go to the
um if you have a reference to a cach you
can go cach dot like the that cach
variable do add and then pass a request
object to it and then what what it will
do is it will automatically issue that
request and um store the response in the
cache and then you can just retrieve the
response so I had a scenario somewhere
where I didn't have access to fetch and
I used that um to
Alternative is it will not it will not
send post requests ah so just just
forget so that could be a way if you
don't have access to fure um the xhr
request or whatever in some like very
weird sandx sandbox environment or
something like that that's too specific
I didn't didn't want to say that yeah
that's that's a that that is very
interesting um so I I think I think that
this the way that they used it in this
scenario though the service worker right
yeah so if I if I want to get back to
the um to the explanation of the actual
bug here um
the the scenario is if the um service
worker uses the cash API as like
intended um just to store like responses
and then like when it matches the
response in some Cas it will um return
it what's interesting is the cach that I
mentioned you open like with a specific
identifier and I didn't know that until
now it's sort of shared in the whole
origin sort of like local storage crazy
yeah so if you from like even a normal
page in that origin which is sort of
less privileged than the service worker
if
you um use caches do open with the same
identifier you can um get a reference to
the same cash and start manipulating it
and then you can add like
a request response per where the
response say like a malicious HTML
payload and now if the service worker
matches that in some request hopefully
top level navigation or something like
that so the response
renders um then um you will get xss
there I guess you can also um whole
thing I guess you can also uh like
intercept JS resources stuff like that
yeah that's that's kind of the one that
I was thinking of is like okay you know
this service worker is there to do
caching on like you know JS resources or
or or other resources that that might
need to to be reloaded a bunch of times
um and so and so then by poisoning that
response you pivot your your access to a
much larger variety of pages yeah the
sort of and make it persistent yeah
that's the thing a larger variety of
pages is like you could always just
window. open and um yeah and do stuff
with that and because they're same
origin this is like a very weird attack
scenario because it's you have xss which
is usually like game over but you're
trying to escalate it further to make it
persistent which in some cases you will
have to do it's very helpful I think
yeah say it's like they have um some
flow where they when they um
authenticate the user they only
authenticate them in that specific TB
right say with session storage yeah or
there's session St right session storage
is the one that came to mind for me
because it's isolated to the tab then
you want to make yourself your self your
xss persistent right so that whenever
they open any tab they will get xss so
the next time they log in they will get
xss um so this is sort of a way to do
that another way to do that would be
maybe reflection of a cookie of local
storage stuff like that that that's what
we typically use that's very interesting
though yeah because this widely
applicable very globally applicable it's
just I have no idea how you're supposed
to mitigate that and even not even like
from the Chrome perspective because are
they just going to change the behavior
they can't cuz I'm sure there's Legacy
stuff with it I think I think we've got
this one unlock I think we're going to
have this this escalation for a while
yeah all right man very interesting we
made
it some some very long episodes uh and I
appreciate uh that you allow me to to
milk your brain for every last little
bit of knowledge that I can get um I'm
still keeping some some stuff but I
disclosed more than I initially intended
to there we go um all right man well
thanks for coming on and I appreciate
you as always thanks for having me again
peace dude peace and that's a wrap on
this episode of critical thinking thanks
so much for listening and if you want
more critical thinking content head over
to ctbb doow Discord join the Discord
there's lots of great conversations and
chats going on over there and if you
want to support the show there's the
Discord subscriber tiers which give you
access to master classes am hack alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there
[Music]